1-language.com 2013-04-20

# Learn English - Learn English as a Second Language - ESL

Privacy Policy for www.1-language.com 

At 1-language.com, the privacy of our visitors is extremely important to us. This privacy policy document outlines the types of personal information received and collected by 1-language.com and how these bits of information are used. 

**Log Files**

Like many other Web sites, 1-language.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. 

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

This website uses cookies to store information about visitor's preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user accesses or visits, and/or customize Web page content based on the visitor's browser type or other information that the visitor sends via his or her browser. 

**DoubleClick DART Cookie**

.:: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site.  
.:: Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to 1-language.com and other sites on the Internet.   
.:: Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL - http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html 

We use third-party ad networks to serve advertisements on this site. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Other technologies ( such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons ) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and / or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

This website has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. Our privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites. 

This privacy statement covers the site www.1-language.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users' privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices.

1\. What personally identifiable information 1-language.com collects.

2\. What personally identifiable information third parties collect through the Web site.

3\. What organization collects the information. 

4\. How 1-language.com uses the information.

5\. With whom 1-language.com may share user information. 

6\. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information. 

7\. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under 1-language.com control. 

8\. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact 1-language at admin@1-language.com.

**Information Collection and Use**  

**Information Collection**  
\------------------------------  

**Registration**  
Registration is not required to use this site, with the exception of the Video Center section where a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information including a username, password, and valid email address. We do not use this information, but it is passed on to RealEnglisn.com to contact the user about services on their site for which the user has expressed interest. 1-language.com also has Discussion Forums which have optional registration. For more details see "Profile" below.

**Information Use**  
All information collected by 1-language.com is of a non-personal nature except the Discussion Forums and the Video Center. 1-language.com records aggregate information such as number of users, location, server type, and method of arriving at 1-language.com. The Discussion Forums allow users to optionally register information such as username, password, location, and interests. This information is not sold or given to third parties under any circumstances. The Discussion Forums are run using PHPBB2 software which uses a MySQL database, and so present a very small security risk from hacking attempts. The Video Center requires a valid email address, username and password which are not used by 1-language.com, but are passed on to RealEnglish.com. 

**Profile**  
1-language.com collects profiles from our discussion forums which use PHPBB2 software. Registration for these forums is not required, and if a users chooses to register only an email address is required. Users may also provide information such as location, occupation, interests and contact information.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user¡¯s computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user¡¯s hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. 

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. 

**Third Party Advertising**  
1-language.com currently has no third party advertising.

This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by 1-language.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. 

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user¡¯s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. [IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to enable our Web-based service.] [We use a tracking utility called [XXXX] that uses log files to analyze user movement.][Webtrendslive users may have further obligations of particular language per their license with Webtrendslive. See your license agreement.] [See the Profile section below.] 

**Communications from the Site  
\---------------------------------**

**Special Offers and Updates**  
We send all new members a welcoming email to verify password and username for the Video Center and Discussion Forums. Established members will occasionally receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications.

**Newsletter**  
1-language.com does not currently have a newsletter. If we do have a newsletter our policy is as follows:  
If a user wishes to subscribe to our newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications.

**Service Announcements**  
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

**Customer Service**  
We communicate with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and in regards to issues relating to their account we reply via email or phone, in accordance with the users wishes.

**Sharing  
\--------- **

**Legal Disclaimer**  
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.

**Aggregate Information** (non-personally identifiable)  
We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personally identifiable information.

**Third Party Advertisers**  
1-language.com does not currently have third-party advertisers.

These are the instances in which we will share users¡¯ personal information:

We Share Personal Information in one instance, where users register for the Video Center. We partner with RealEnglish.com to provide the videos and exercises in this section. When the user signs up for these particular services, we share names, or other contact information such as email addresses that is necessary for the third party to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services, and providing information requested by the user in the registration process.

**Links**  
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, 1-language.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Chat Rooms, Message Boards, and Public Forums**  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, by posting personal information online that is publicly accessible, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

**Security**  
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users¡¯ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to [admin@1-language.com](mailto:admin@1-language.com).

**  
Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If, however, we are going to use users¡¯ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email.

**Contact Information**  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

Email - admin@1-language.com
